

# Daniel A. Sánchez R.

# Computer Science Engineer

El Vendrell, Tarragona Phone.: (+34) 603-249528

Email: <a href="mailto:ingdanielsanchezve@gmail.com">ingdanielsanchezve@gmail.com</a> Website: <a href="mailto:https://iamdanielsanchez.ml">https://iamdanielsanchez.ml</a>

LinkedIn: https://ve.linkedin.com/in/ingdanielsanchezvzla

Skype: live:ing.danielsanchez

### Summary

Computer engineer with a large web development and software engineering experience using LAMP and MEAN stacks, knowledge in responsive web site development, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Javascript ES5 y ES6, Jquery, Ajax, AngularJS, BackboneJS, Underscore, Mustache, GruntJs, VueJs, NuxtJs, NodeJs, MochaJs, ChaiJs, PHP5, PHP7, Laravel Framework, SQL, MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, Firebird, MongoDB Databases, Linux, GIT, SVN, Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, LinkedIn, Pinterest, Mailchimp and PayU developers APIs, Web Services and RESTful APIs development, Test Driven Development TDD, Unit Testing, MVC software architecture pattern, Apache module implementation, Linux Server Administration (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS), SEO knowledges, PI-SQL, Application Development with Oracle Developer Suite 6, Visual Studio 6, Agile development methodologies XP and SCRUM.

## Experience

### Senior Frontend Developer

Cires21 (Remote – Madrid, SP)

07/2019 - Present

- UI and UX design of the SAAS product for content broadcasting C21 Live Director.
- Views design using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap CSS and the ElementUI component framework for VueJS.
- Use VueJs, Typescript and Javascript ES6 for frontend development.
- Consume JSON responses returned from the Backend RESTful API endpoints.
- Use Composer dependencies manager for PHP and NPM, YARN and PNPM for Javascript.
- Use VideoJS to integrate video players using the Streaming HLS protocol.
- Use NuxtJs, Bootstrap CSS and Element UI to create the views and components frontend code for Video-MOS tool used to Measure Video Content Quality and Monitoring the content transmission quality.
- Use CanvasJs to create and display responsive HTML5 graphics to represent video quality and streaming quality measurement data in pie charts, bar charts, and line charts.
- Creation of Ajax queries to consult the data stored in the databases and the responses of from the encoders using Axios and Asynchronous functions.

Daniel A. Sánchez R. - Phone: (+34) 603-249528 - email: ingdanielsanchezve@gmail.com - skype: live:ing.danielsanchez

Website: https://iamdanielsanchez.ml

- Methods and Classes development using PHP 5 and PHP 7 in the Backend to communicate the data between the frontend and the database, implementing business logic, parsing and formatting input data from the application and responses.
- Use Docker to create images of the application.
- Use Okteto Cloud to develop Kubernetes K8s namespaces in the cloud.
- Use Git as a version control system.
- Use GitLab boards to manage Development Issues and user stories.
- Use Gitlab and Github as version control repositories store and its tools for development of collaborative software in the company projects.
- Use of messaging and communication tools such as Slack, Google Meet, Google Hangout, Skype.

#### Senior Frontend Developer

# Cecropia Solutions – Reliq health technologies (Remote – Ontario, CA) 04/2018 –07/2018

- Using AngularJs for the frontend code the UI.
- Create perfect pixel UI from design.
- Consume RESTful Api from backend endpoints.
- Create ajax request to the server to query the data stored in the system database and render in the interface using backend endpoints.
- Use differents Jquery libraries to render charts with patients measures data.
- Design Html templates using css framework Twitter Bootstrap.
- Using Atlasian Jiira to manage the user history, comments and development requests.
- Using Atlasian Confluence for tickets documentations.
- Using Atlasian Bitbucket as hosting service for repositories and Git as control version system for the project code.
- Using SCRUM Agile methodology as software development methodology with sprint daily standup, sprint look ahead, sprint review and sprint retrospective meetings.

# Cecropia Solutions – Berkery Noyes LLC (Remote – New York, USA) 07/2017 –03/2018

- Using Javascript libraries to code the bussines logic for the UI.
- Render Project Views using underscore templates.
- Fetching data from database and render in the system views.
- Use BackboneJS, jQuery libraries and Mustache templates for the application frontend code.
- Create Ajax request to the server to query the data stored in the system database and render to the interface.
- Use Javascript to Create Validations to prevent user data entry errors.
- Test-driven development (TDD) using Chails and Sinonls to create unit tests to verify the developed code work properly.
- Use TreeJS to display user acquitions types listed in the differents listbox.
- Design views templates using css framework Twitter Bootstrap.
- Using Jiira to manage the user history, comments and development requests
- Using Git as control version system for the project code.

#### Chief Technology Officer – CTO

#### Soy Empleo (Remote – Medellin, Colombia)

10/2015 - 09/2017

- Create Backlogs, User Histories and developments tasks accord to SCRUM methodoly.
- Manage and Lead Work of frontend, backend and testing teams.
- Implementing and software setup in Linux servers. (Apache, MySQL, PHP, NodeJs, NPM, Mongo, Supervisor, Git, Beanstalk).
- Implementing SEO strategies in the company web sites.
- MongoDB database (Install, Update and Database Administration, Database Management, Index Creation, Backups, Restores, Users Authentication, Database Modeling, Storage Engine Configuration).
- Implementing colaborative software development tools (Git, Trello, Google Drive, Slack, Zoom).
- Creating and Modeling Database Collections using MongoDb.
- Linux servers Administration in Amazon Web Service EC2 instances (AWS)
- Backend Software Development using Laravel Framework 5.4.
- Frontend Software Development using AngularJs and VueJs.
- Test-driven development (TDD) using PHPUnit to create unit tests to verify the developed code work properly.
- UI design using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Fontawesome, Glyphicons.

#### Full Stack Developer

#### Octopus C.A. (Valencia, Venezuela)

09/2013 - 11/2015

- Development and implementing of backend scripts using PHP, Laravel, NodeJs.
- Integration with Facebook APIs, Twitter APIs, Instagram APIs and Pinterest APIs.
- MySQL ( Database Administration, Database Management, Index Creation, Backups, Restores, Users Management, Database Modeling, Functions and store procedures development).
- MongoDB (Install, Update and Database Administration, Database Management, Index Creation, Backups, Restores, Users Authentication, Database Modeling, Storage Engine Configuration).
- Implementing and configuration of software in Linux servers. (Apache, MySQL, PHP, NodeJs, NPM, Mongo, Supervisor, Git, Beanstalk).
- Implementing SEO strategies for the bussiness web sites.
- Development and implementing of frontend scripts using Jquery, Javascript, Angular, Blade, Mustache, Grunt.
- UI Development with HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Fontawesome, Glyphicons.

### Development Analyst II

Valencia City Hall(Valencia, Venezuela)

01/2012 - 07/2014

- Development and maintenance of the Applications and Websites of the Valencia City Hall using LAMP stack technologies.
- Use jQuery to validate, create ajax requests and and add animations for the websites.
- Development and maintenance of the tax collection system of the Valencia City Hall using

- Oracle de Developer Suite (Forms y Reports).
- Development of SQL scripts, Database Modeling, Tables, Views, Functions and Procedures in Oracle using TOAD for Oracle.
- Development of modules and maintenance of the system of civilian register of the Valencia City Hall using Visual Basic 6, Crystal Reports, MySQL.

#### Technological Process Analyst II

Valencia City Hall(Valencia, Venezuela) 08/2008 – 01/2012

- Applications development using Oracle de Developer Suite (Forms y Reports).
- Web applications development using LAMP stack.
- Aplications Development using Visual Basic 6, MySql and Crystal Reports using Server Client Model.
- MySQL Databases Administration.

#### Education

#### Computer Science Engineer

Valencia Technological Institute September 2009 – June 2012

### Web Application Development Diplomature

Jose Antonio Paéz University September 2007 – April 2008

#### Technician in computer science

Valencia Technological Institute September 2002 – June 2008

#### Skills

- Html 5
- Css 3
- Javascript ES6
- JQuery
- BackboneJs
- Ajax
- AngularJs
- VueJs
- Typescript
- AWS
- Google Cloud
- Docker

- Kubernetes
  - K8s
- Grunt
- NodeJs
- Underscore
- Mustache
- Linux
- Apache
- PHP
- Laravel
- MySQL
- SQL

- Oracle
- PI-SQL
- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB
- Toad
- Facebook API
- Twitter API
- Instagram API
- LinkedIn API
- Pinterest API
- TDD

Languages

Spanish

Mother Language

English

Fluent

French
Reading